# **Julian Beard**

Software Engineer

(517) 626.4000 · badjab326@gmail.com · Murrieta, CA · julianbeard.codes · in/Julian-A-Beard · github.com/badjab326

Software engineering graduate from General Assembly who's spent nearly ten years in various team based, customer facing positions, and gained an extensive repertoire of communication, team building and resource management skills.

## **SKILLS**

**Languages** - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python | **Libraries and Frameworks** - React, Node.js, Express.js, Django **Database** - PostgreSQL, Sequelize, ORM, MongoDB, Mongoose, ODM | **Other** - RESTful Routing JSON

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

2022 - Present

## What2Play

- Built from the ground up using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Ajax.
- Utilized an API to retrieve photos and information of random video games based on user preferences.
- Styled using flexbox, custom fonts and manually edited backgrounds.
- Designed with mobile browsers in mind via responsive design.

#### Collarchive

- Manufactured multi-page create, read, update, delete (CRUD) app using Embedded JavaScript.
- Made RESTful API fetch calls to an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling all CRUD operations, and tested all backend routes during development using Postman.
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections.
- Adapted extensive CSS to generate an intuitively designed front-end.

#### **Avatar Yearbook**

- Created a digital yearbook for bootcamp graduates to keep in touch and solidify professional contacts.
- Used React.js to serve the front-end with Javascript methods and functions.
- Served the back-end of the application using Express methods and functions utilizing MongoDB database management.
- Added Backend user authentication/authorization using Google Firebase.
- Worked as Lead Backend Dev with a team of talented software engineers.

#### Gym Planner

- Produced app designed to give users the ability to digitally plan, track and optimize their workouts.
- Constructed with Python, Django, Materialize CSS and PostgreSQL
- Implemented full user authentication and authorization, as well as admin functionality.
- Modeled with MVT architecture.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Alaska Airlines, Flight Attendant | Los Angeles, CA

Oct. 2017 - May 2022

- Enforced time management skills to work under tight time constraints to deliver optimal and safe service.
- Used strong communication and team management skills to work with highly diverse groups of people.
- Exerted patience and flexibility with adapting to constant changes in both the industry, and individual flights.
- Consistently learned and incorporated new skills and safety procedures into my workflow as needed.
- Handled secure information with care and confidence.

#### Pacific Pool Tile, Office Manager | Wildomar, CA

Jan. 2017 - Oct. 2017

- Managed several different avenues of business including sales, rentals, construction and payroll.
- Created strong customer relationships to guarantee repeat sales and ease of operations.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE**

Software Engineering Immersive

April 2022 - July 2022

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.